cutshort.io 2019-06-09

# Privacy | CutShort

Introduction

This Privacy Policy (effective from 3rd June 2019 i.e. 'Effective Date') describes our practices regarding use, maintenance, and disclosure of Personal Information that we collect through the Channels defined hereunder. You can be assured that any Personal Information that you disclose to us will be treated only in the manner described in this policy.  
Whenever this Policy mentions 'CUTSHORT' or 'we' or 'us' or 'our', it refers to the AppyHappy Software Private Limited, which is responsible for your information under this Privacy Policy.  
We urge you to read this Policy thoroughly. By accessing our website/mobile app and using our Channels, you will have represented your agreement to this policy and bound by its terms. Kindly note, this policy does not apply to third-party websites, products, or services even if they link to our Channels, and You should consider the privacy practices of those third-parties carefully.  
By using the Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the practices described in this Privacy Policy, please do not provide us with your personal information or interact with the Site/app.  
Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of use

1\. Scope of the Privacy Policy

  1. This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect through the following (collectively referred to as 'Channels')
    1. Cutshort web platform, tools and services accessible via the same
    2. Websites – www.cutshort.io, www.cutshort.ai
    3. Cutshort mobile application
    4. Our services for configuration, setup and training
    5. Customer interface channels
    6. Social networking sites
    7. Electronic communications
  2. Our privacy and security practices in connection with the access and use of our Channels are governed by the TERMS OF USE, which are a binding contract between the User (respectively, collectively referred to as 'You') and us

2\. Information we collect

  1. We may collect and retain the following information (Personal Data) from and about you if you interact with us through the Site'Channels')
    1. Your phone numbers, your email id and password which you have entered in the Channels; work experience information, educational information, salary, resume and social profiles links
    2. For your benefit, you may opt to import and sync your contacts, address books or networks from 3rd party services including but not limited to Google, Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Dribbble, GitHub & StackExchange. In such cases, we may receive your contacts (including contact information, your service provider(s). If you sync your email or calendars with our Services, we will collect your 'email header' and calendar meeting information (e.g. times, places, attendees and contacts)
    3. your location, website browsing patterns (e.g., through cookies) and purchase history; user activity and use of the Service (e.g. among other things, page views, IP address, requested URLs, referring URLs, visit date and length, and file type requests)
    4. your payment details, billing and delivery addresses, a credit / debit card number and a credit / debit card expiration date and/ or other payment instrument details
  2. We collect information about you when you send, receive, or engage with messages in connection with our Services. For example, if you get a message from another user, we track whether you have acted on it and will send you reminders. We may also analyse these messages algorithmically to make better suggestions for you and other users
  3. We may also collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Website or use our Service which may include information such as browser type, browser version, your computer's Internet Protocol (IP) address, internet service provider, date/time stamp, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, the information you search for, local and language preferences, identification numbers associated with your devices, your mobile carrier, and system configuration information, the time spent on those pages usage information, and other statistics

3\. How you can choose how we should use your Personal Data

  1. We get access to above mentioned information when you
    1. Access the Channels
    2. Register, subscribe, or create an account with Cutshort 
    3. Open or respond to our emails
    4. Contact customer service or use other customer support tools
    5. Visit any page online that displays our ads or content
    6. Connect or link to any Website via social networking sites
    7. Provide information to our vendors
  2. As a Cutshort user, you have the power to control how we use the Personal Data that we collect
    1. You can manage your email, SMS and notice preferences by adjusting the settings in your web browser
    2. You can also manage your subscriptions by following subscription management instructions contained in any commercial emails that we send you
  3. Please note that even if you decide not to subscribe to, or to unsubscribe, from promotional email messages, we may still need to contact you with important transactional information related to your account with Cutshort and your purchases/access of CUTSHORT Device
  4. You hereby consent to receive communications by SMS, email or calls from CUTSHORT with regard to the services provided by it
  5. You may manage how your web browser or mobile device handles cookies by adjusting its privacy and security settings. Please refer to Paragraph 10 of this Policy for information of Cookies for more information
  6. You may also manage the sharing of certain personal data with us when you connect with us through social networking platforms or applications. You may adjust our permissions and manage the interactivity between us and your social networking account or your mobile device

4\. How we use your Personal Data

We process and use your Personal Data for the following purposes enumerated below. The list is not an exhaustive one. We use the information for many other purposes including the following

  1. To personalise your account with CUTSHORT
  2. Facilitate and process orders – for example, for and other goods and services 
  3. Determine your eligibility for certain types of offers, products or services that may be of interest to you, and analyse advertising effectiveness 
  4. Answer your questions and respond to your requests 
  5. Communicate and provide additional information that may be of interest to you about us, the sellers and our business partners 
  6. Send you reminders, technical notices, updates, security alerts, support and administrative messages, service bulletins, marketing messages, and requested information, including on behalf of business partners 
  7. Manage our everyday business needs, such as administration of Channels, analytics, fraud prevention, and enforcement of our corporate reporting obligations or to comply with the law 
  8. Comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements 
  9. Enhance other information we have about you to help us better understand you, determine your interests and provide you with more relevant and compelling services 
  10. To maintain, operate and improve the site 
  11. To authenticate your registration through OTP or otherwise

5\. How we disclose your Personal Data

We are not in the business of selling or renting Personal Data. We will not share your Personal Data with third parties, except in the following manner

  1. If you are a Candidate, then, with the Recruiters, so they can contact You
  2. in case of a merger, acquisition or reorganization with a purchaser of our company or all or substantially all of our assets
  3. to comply with legal orders and government requests, or as needed to support auditing, compliance
  4. to combat fraud or criminal activity, and to protect our rights or those of our affiliates, business partners and users, or as part of legal proceedings affecting Cutshort
  5. in response to a legal process, including to law enforcement agencies, regulators, and courts
  6. With your consent or as otherwise required or permitted by law

We may disclose non-personal information in the aggregate to third parties (e.g. Advertisers) relating to user activities, salaries, professional data and behaviour on the Channels

6\. Security and Visibility of Personal Data

  1. We use strict security measures to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of Your Personal Data and to protect your Personal Data against unauthorized access or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction
  2. We shall, however, not be responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties that receive your Personal Data
  3. Neither we nor our representatives will ask you for your password or other Personal Data, including financial information. Please treat requests for your password or other personal information as suspicious and promptly contact us
  4. When You use the Channels to find career opportunities, we show your information (called "talent card") to only the users registered as Recruiters and don't share it on social networks or search engines. We also offer you an option to hide your talent card from specific employers by specifying companies and will make reasonable efforts to do so, however, we provide no guarantees to such an effect
  5. When You use the Channels for any other purpose such as professional growth, content share and recruiting, your content such as job will be visible to all users, be shared on social networks and search engines
  6. We have put in place reasonable and necessary organisational and physical measures and are implementing and updating appropriate administrative, technical, organizational and physical security measures of commercially acceptable security standards to help protect your information against unauthorized access, loss, destruction, use, alteration or disclosure of any information we store. Some of the safeguards we use to protect your information are firewalls and information access controls

7\. Data Transmission and Storage

  1. The information collected by us may be sent to servers located in the United States and/or other countries around the world
  2. In addition, we may display advertisements on our service from third parties (e.g. partners, advertising companies, and ad networks). These third parties use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to measure the effectiveness of their advertisement. We do not provide any personal information to these third parties

8\. User's Rights in relation to Personal Data

  1. By keeping your personal data updated you can help us to ensure that we can respect your preferences and offer you the goods and services that are most relevant to you
  2. You have a right to have your Personal Data maintained by us removed from our systems. You can also at any time unsubscribe from our services, newsletters, e-mailers. Provided that, notwithstanding such request, this data may be retained if required to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. We may also retain your Personal Data and maintain a record of your transactions for financial reporting or other compliance purposes
  3. In case you opt to delete your account, we shall retain your Personal Data for upto six months after which, we shall delete all your Data along with any Personal Data. When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible

9\. Public Posts

The Channels may contain connections to areas where you may be able to publicly post information, communicate with others such as discussion boards or blogs, review products etc., and otherwise submit your own original content. Prior to posting in these areas, please read our TERMS OF USE carefully. All the information you post may be accessible to anyone with Internet access, and any information you include in your posting may be read, collected, and used by others

10\. Messages and Notifications

  1. We use your email address to provide services in connection with the Service, such as updates, notifications, and reminders, and to contact you on behalf of other users of the Service who send you communication, among other things
  2. At times, we will notify you by email about updates, changes, and other service related information. We will never ask you for your password or other personal information in those notifications and communication, or in any other communication from us

11\. Privacy Policies of Third Parties

  1. We employ third parties to perform certain tasks to facilitate our services and to assist us in analyzing its usage. We may transfer certain Personal Data to these third parties, but this transfer will be subject to your explicit consent and the TERMS OF USE. These third parties have access to your Personal Data albeit only to perform specific tasks on our behalf and are contractually and otherwise obligated not to disclose or use your information for any other purpose
  2. This Privacy Policy only addresses the collection, processing and use (including disclosure) of information by us through your interaction with the Channels. Other websites that may be accessible through links from the Site may have their own privacy policies and personal information collection, processing, use, and disclosure practices. Our business partners may also have their own privacy policies. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy policies provided by these other parties prior to providing them with information or taking advantage of a sponsored offer or promotion

12\. Cookies

  1. Cookies are unique identifiers, usually made up of small bits of text or code. Cookies are usually stored on your device or in your web browser and they send certain information back to the party who served the cookie. When we say cookies we are actually referring to a broader range of technologies than just cookies, including web beacons, clear gifs, pixels and other similar technologies. When we say first-party cookies we mean cookies that are served by Cutshort .com. When we say third party cookies we mean cookies that are served by non-Cutshort .com parties
  2. We use cookies to ensure that you have the best possible experience while using our Service. Cookies are used in order to better understand how applications and websites work and to optimize online and mobile experiences. Cookies do this by allowing the party serving the cookie to analyse a website’s or mobile app’s performance, to identify certain users anonymously and remember their preferences, to better understand whether a computer or device (and probably its user) has visited a website previously and to serve personalised advertisements
  3. Consent: By using our Website or Channels, using any services provided through the Site, or receiving our emails, you consent to the use of cookies in accordance with this clause as 'Cookies Policy'
  4. Intent: This Privacy Policy sets out how we, and third parties we authorize, use cookies when you interact with our Site or the services offered via the Site. Our Privacy Policy explains what we do (and don't do) with the information, including any personal data we may collect about you. Please read them both
  5. Cookies in E-mails: Our emails contain cookies that track whether you open our emails and whether you click any links within them. The cookies used in our emails to monitor these behaviours are unique to each email and are not stored on your computer or mobile device
  6. Cookies and Browser settings: You may be able to avoid certain cookies by configuring your browser settings or opting-out directly with the party that operates and controls the cookie. Please check your browser settings for more information. Kindly note that in case you opt to decline cookies and flush out the cookies from your computer, it will reduce the functionality of our Service

13\. Account Deactivation, Reactivation and Deletion

  1. At any point, you may deactivate your account from your account settings page. Once deactivated, your personal data will stop being visible to others on our Services and you will be unsubscribed from all messages, emails, notifications from us. Some information such as messages/communications you have sent or content you have already shared with other CutShort users using any of our Services will remain visible to others
  2. We retain your Personal Data even after you have deactivate your account to prevent fraud and abuse and enforce our Terms of Use
  3. You may reactivate your account yourself in the future by successfully verifying your account by proving ownership of your registered email address or mobile number
  4. You may, at any point request us to delete your account, by contacting our support team, which shall take upto 15 business days. Once deleted, neither You nor other users shall be able to view Your Data including account information, communications etc. however, the same shall remain in our systems for upto 6 months (for legal and other compliances) after which, it shall be deleted. You shall not be allowed to reactivate your account once you exercise the option of deletion of the account. Upon deletion, some information such as messages/communications/resumes/documents you have sent or content you have shared on the Channels will remain visible to others
  5. Upon deactivation or deletion of your account, we attempt to take all necessary measures to ensure that Your Personal Data is not visible to other users, however, we disclaim all liability if such data has been previously downloaded by any user prior to such deactivation or deletion of the account

14\. Personal Data of Children

We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under 18. If you are a child under the age of 18, do not submit any Personal Data to us. If you are a parent or guardian, we encourage you to instruct your children not to disclose any Personal Data without your consent

15\. GDPR

We do not deliberately reach out or intend to collect any Personal Data of persons from the European Union. If you are a person from the European Union, do not submit your Personal Data to us

16\. Contact Us

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy or about our privacy practices, please contact us by email at [hello@cutshort.io](mailto:hello@cutshort.io)

17\. Modifications in Privacy Policy

We will routinely update this Privacy Policy to improve our practices and to reflect new or different privacy practices, such as when we add new services, functionality or features. You can determine when this version of the Privacy Policy was adopted by referring to the 'Effective Date' above
